SUMMARY

9 years of programming experience in c++ and Java in both research and industry.

5 years of computational physics research focusing on quantum Monte Carlo simulation.

1 years of experience in developing semiconductor transistor-level analog simulation software.

[External Project] Implemented and coded option pricing algorithms (analytical and Monte Carlo) based various different models (Black-Scholes, Heston).

EXPERIENCE

Principal Software Engineer, Cadence Design Systems, Inc. Nov.2020- Now

Designed and developed EDA analog simulation software Spectre using c++. Responsible for postlayout EMIR analysis feature.

Application Engineer, Advantest America, Inc. July.2013-Feb.2020

Developed and delivered system on chip(SoC) test programs for Advantest 93K automated tester platform.

Achievement Highlights

- Developed test methods in C++/java for DC test, digital test, RF test.
- Developed universal test method library for On-Die Parametric test on different TI DSP device, provide device characterization results to R&D.
- Built data analysis tool using python(including scipy, pandas library) to do data analysis.

Research Assistant, Department of Physics, North Carolina State University, Jun.2009-Jun.2013 Conducted computational physics research focusing on electronic structure using quantum Monte Carlo method, developed and maintained computational software code in C++ for 3 years. *Achievement Highlights*

- Conducted quantum Monte Carlo research on linux-based supercomputers.
- Applied quantum Monte Carlo to evaluate the expectation value of physical quantities for solid state and semiconductor systems.
- Carried out numerical wavefunction optimizations(steep descent, quasi-Newton, etc.) to reduce the data fluctuation.
- Evaluated the dipole moment of weakly bonded ultracold molecules precisely and provided the data with good quality to research funding agency.
- Developed, contributed quantum Monte Carlo software package by designing every class and method independently using C++(10k lines) to calculate spin-orbit interaction.

EDUCATION

• Ph.D Physics

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA, Dec.2013 GPA:3.63/4.0

• B.S. Physics, Minor in Economics Shanghai Jiaotong University, Shanghai, China, Jun.2007